Guide to the Donald Gordon Papers, 1900-1988 UA.90.F46
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Ernst Ludwig Kirchner, I.
  - Inventory of Kirchner Works, 1.
    - Tightrope Act (Drahtseilleute), 502, 1917-1918 (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - The Hospital Attendant (Der Krankenwärter), 503, 1917-1918 (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - The Hospital Attendant Brühlmann (Krankenpfleger Brühlmann), 504, 1917-1918 (Box 3, Folder 78)
    - View of the Church in Mondstein (Blick auf die Kirche in Mondstei), 505, 1917-1918 (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - Sand Mountairs in Engadine (Sandberge Engadin), 506, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - Village in Wallis Canton (Dorf im Wallis), 507, 1917-1918 (Box 3, Folder 81)
    - Fishing Cabin on Lake Constance (Fischerh↔tte am Bodensee), 508, 1918-1918 (Box 3, Folder 82)
    - View of Lake Constance at Kreuzlingen (Bodenseelandschaft bei Kreuzlingen), 509, 1917-1918/1920 (Box 3, Folder 83)
    - Greenhouse and Garden (Gewächshaus im Garten), 510, 1917-1918/1920 (Box 3, Folder 84)
    - Still Life with Pitchers and Candle (Stilleben mit Krügen und Kerze), 511, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 85)
    - Mountain Peaks (Berggipfel), 512, 1918 (Box 3, Folder 86)
    - Mountain Sunset near Davos (Sonnenuntergang in den Davoser Bergen), 513, 1918 (Box 3, Folder 87)
    - Portrait of Nele van de Velde (Porträt Nele van de Velde), 514, 1918 (Box 3, Folder 88)
    - Yellow Tulips; Still Life with "Bubu de Montparnasse" (Gelbe Tulpen; Stilleben mit "Bubu de Montparnasse), 515, 1918 (Box 3, Folder 89)
    - Young Shepherd with Flowers (Junger Hirte mit Blume), 516, 1918 (Box 3, Folder 90)
    - Boy with Candy (Junge mit Bonbontüte), 517, 1918 (Box 3, Folder 91)
    - Alpine Kitchen (Alpküche), 518, 1918 (Box 3, Folder 92)
    - Old Hut (Alte Sennhütte), 519, 1918 (Box 3, Folder 93)
    - Farmer with Cows (Bauer mit Kühen), 520, 1918 (Box 3, Folder 94)
    - Timberline (Baumgrenze), 521, 1918 (Box 3, Folder 95)
    - Rising Moon (Aufgehender Mond), 522, 1918 (Box 3, Folder 96)
    - Staffelalp in Fog (Staffelalp im Nebel), 523, 1918 (Box 3, Folder 97)
    - Cyclamen (Alpenveilchen), 524, 1918 (Box 3, Folder 98)
    - Goatherd in the Morning (Ziegenhirt am Morgen), 525, 1918 (Box 3, Folder 99)
    - Staffelalp Landscape (Landschaft auf der Staffelalp), 526, 1918 (Box 3, Folder 100)
    - Life in the Alps, Triptych (Alplebel, Triptychon), 527, 1918 (Box 3, Folder 101)
    - Alpine Huts with Two Figures (Alphütte mit zwei Figuren), 528, 1918 (Box 3, Folder 102)
    - Staffelalp Forest Glen (Waldschlucht Staffel), 529, 1918 (Box 3, Folder 103)
    - Trees in Mountain Forest (Bergwaldbäume), 530, 1918 (Box 3, Folder 104)
    - Mountain Forest (Bergwald), 531, 1918/1920 (Box 3, Folder 105)
    - Walkers Resting (Rastende Spaziergänger), 532, 1918 (Box 3, Folder 106)
    - Huts in Autumn (Hütte im Herbst), 533, 1918 (Box 3, Folder 107)
    - Staffelalp with Dairy Farm (Staffelalp mit Sennerei), 534, 1918-1919 (Box 3, Folder 108)
    - Staffelalp Road (Staffelweg), 535, 1918-1919 (Box 3, Folder 109)
    - View of Valley with Church (Blick ins Tal mit Münster), 536, 1918-1919 (Box 3, Folder 110)
    - Staffelalp Huts (Staffelalphütten), 537, 1918-1919 (Box 3, Folder 111)
    - House on the Staffelalp (Haus auf der Staffel), 538, 1918-1919 (Box 3, Folder 112)
    - Ascending the Alps (Alpaufzug), 539, 1918-1919 (Box 3, Folder 113)
    - Cows in the Meadow (Kühe in der Weise), 540, 1918-1919 (Box 3, Folder 114)
    - Cows in the Alps (Kühe auf der Alp), 541, 1918-1919 (Box 3, Folder 115)
    - Grazing Heifers (Galtviehweide), 542, 1918-1919 (Box 3, Folder 116)
    - Cows Descending (Absteigende Kühe), 543, 1918-1919 (Box 3, Folder 117)
    - Grazing Cows (Wiedende Kühe), 544, 1918-1919 (Box 3, Folder 118)
    - Goats in the Mountains (Ziegen im Berg), 545, 1918/1920 (Box 3, Folder 119)
    - Cow Stable; Farmer Milking (Kuhstall; Alpbauer beim Melken), 546, 1918/1920 (Box 3, Folder 120)
    - Pink Roses (Rosa Rosen), 547, 1918 (Box 3, Folder 121)
    - Still Life with Oval Table (Stilleben mit ovalem Tisch), 548, 1918-1919 (Box 3, Folder 122)
    - Flowerpot and Sugarbox; Flowers (Blumentopf und Zuckerdose; Blumen), 549, 1918-1919 (Box 3, Folder 123)
    - Still Life with Lillies (Stilleben mit Lilien), 550, 1918-1919 (Box 3, Folder 124)
    - African Bowl, Flowers, and Fruit (Negerschale, Blumen und Früchte), 551, 1918-1919 (Box 3, Folder 125)
    - Still Life with Basket of Fruit (Stilleben mit Früchtekorb), 552, 1918-1919 (Box 3, Folder 126)
    - Cyclamen (Alpenveilchen), 553, 1918-1919 (Box 3, Folder 127)
    - Maryli, 554, 1918-1919 (Box 3, Folder 128)
    - Alps in Snow (Alp im Schnee), 555, 1918-1919 (Box 3, Folder 129)
    - Frauenkirch in Winter (Frauenkirch im Winter), 556, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 130)
    - The Mountains at Klosters (Die Klosterser Berge), 557, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 131)
    - Winter Moon Landscape (Wintermondlandschaft), 558, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 132)
    - Staffelalp with Red Dairy Farm (Staffelalp mit roter Sennerei), 559, 1919-1920 (Box 3, Folder 133)
    - Melting Snow (Schneesmelze), 560, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 134)
    - Rising Moon in the Staffelalp (Mondaufgang auf der Staffelalp), 561, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 135)
    - At the Mountain Lake (Am Bergsee), 562, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 136)
    - Still Life with Flowers and Two Wood Figures (Stilleben mit zwei Holzfiguren und Blumen), 563, 1919-1920 (Box 3, Folder 137)
    - Gray Cat with Cushion (Grauer Kater mit Kissen), 564, 1919-1920 (Box 3, Folder 138)
    - Seehorn, 565, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 139)
    - The Waterfall (Der Wasserfall), 566, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 140)
    - Landscape with Blue Cliffs and Waterfall (Landschaft mit blauen Felsen und Wasserfall), 567, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 141)
    - Mountain Brook (Bergbach), 568, 1919-1920 (Box 3, Folder 142)
    - Junkerboden, 569, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 143)
    - The Mountain; the Staffel Path (Der Berg; Der Weg zur Staffel), 570, 1919-1920 (Box 3, Folder 144)
    - Bend in the Mountian Path (Bergwegkurve), 571, 1919/1920 (Box 3, Folder 145)
    - The Reaper (Der Mäher), 572, 1919/1920 (Box 3, Folder 146)
    - Reapers; the Müller Brothers (Mäher; Die Büder Müller), 573, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 147)
    - The Painter Stirner with Cat (Der Maler Stirner mit Katze), 574, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 148)
    - Farmer's Wife with Children; Mrs. Schmidt with Children (Bäuerin mit Kindern; Frau Schmidt mit Kindern), 575, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 149)
    - The Painter; Self-Portrait (Der Maler; Selbstporträt), 576, 1919-1920 (Box 3, Folder 150)
    - Animals Returning Home (Rükkehr der Tiere), 577, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 151)
    - Tinsenhorn; Mountain Gorge near Monstein (Tinsenhorn; Zügenschlucht bei Monstein), 578, 1919/1920 (Box 3, Folder 152)
    - Cows in the Woods (Kühe im Wald), 579, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 153)
    - Treetrunks in Mountain Forest; Mountain Firs (Bergwaldstämme; Bergtannen), 580, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 154)
    - Forest Path in the Mountains (Bergwaldweg), 581, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 155)
    - Forest Interior (Waldinneres), 582, 1919/1920 (Box 3, Folder 156)
    - Staffelalp by Moonlight (Staffelalp beim Mondschein), 583, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 157)
    - Bluebells (Glockenblumen), 584, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 158)
    - Bluebells on a Mountain Slope (Glockenblumen am Berghang), 585, 1919-1920 (Box 3, Folder 159)
    - Nude Woman and Girl in Mountain Brook (Frauenakt und Mädchen in Bergbach), 586, 1919-1920 (Box 3, Folder 160)
    - Nude at the Spring (Nackte Frau an der Quelle), 587, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 161)
    - Vase with Blue Flowers (Blaue Blumen in Vase), 588, 1919-1920 (Box 3, Folder 162)
    - Mountain Meadow in June (Bergwise im Juni), 589, 1919-1920 (Box 3, Folder 163)
    - Flower Picture (Blumenbild), 590, 1919-1920 (Box 3, Folder 164)
    - Flowers (Blumen), 591, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 165)
    - Red and Blue Flowers (Rote und blaue Blumen), 592, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 166)
    - Dandelions (Löwenzahn), 593, 1919-1920 (Box 3, Folder 167)
    - Landscape in Green and Orange (Landschaft in Grün und Orange), 594, 1919-1920 (Box 3, Folder 168)
    - View into the Gorge (Blick ins Tobel), 595, 1919-1920 (Box 3, Folder 169)
    - Staffelalp Gorge (Tobel der Staffelalp), 596, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 170)
    - Dance between the Women II (Tanz zwischen den Frauen II), 597, 1919/1926 (Box 3, Folder 171)
    - Mountain Village with Pink Cow (Bregdorf mit rosa Kuh), 598, 1919-1920 (Box 3, Folder 172)
    - Three Cabins on the Hill; Red Cabins (Drei Hütte am Hügel; Rote Hütte), 599, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 173)
    - Alp Hut; Red Alp House (Alphütte; Rotes Alphaus), 600, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 174)
    - Alpine Huts and the Tinsenhorn (Alphütten und Tinsenhorn), 601, 1919-1920 (Box 3, Folder 175)
    - Mountain House (Berghaus), 602, 1919-1920 (Box 3, Folder 176)
    - Two Huts on the Staffelalp (Zwei Alphütten auf Staffelalp), 603, 1919-1920 (Box 3, Folder 177)
    - The Painter's House (Das Haus des Malers), 604, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 178)
    - Old Grisons Farmer (Alter Bündner Bauer), 605, 1919-1920 (Box 3, Folder 179)
    - Standing Nude with Sculpture (Stehender Frauenakt im Innenraum), 607, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 180)
    - Standing Nude in Interior (Stehender Frauenakt im Innenraum), 607, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 181)
    - Pink Nude with Cat and Blue Sculpture (Rosa Frauenakt mit Katze und blauer Skulptur), 608, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 182)
    - Seated Nude before Red-Patterned Background (Sitzender nackte Frau vor rotgemustertem Hintergrund), 609, 1919-1920 (Box 3, Folder 183)
    - Orange Nude with Green Background (Oranger Mädchenakt vor grünem Hintergrund), 610, 1919-1920 (Box 3, Folder 184)
    - Two Men in Town (Zwei Männer im Dorf), 611, 1919-1920 (Box 3, Folder 185)
    - Milkmaid (Milchmädchen), 612, 1919/1920 (Box 3, Folder 186)
    - In the Pasture; Peasants at Night (Auf der Alm; Bauern in der Nacht), 613, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 187)
    - Staffelalp in Autumn (Staffelalp im Herbst), 614, 1919-1920 (Box 3, Folder 188)
    - Junkerboden, 615, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 189)
    - Junkerboden seen form the Staffelalp (Junkerboden von der Staffelalp), 616, 1919-1920 (Box 3, Folder 190)
    - Chickens in the Garden (Hühner im Garten), 617, 1919-1920 (Box 3, Folder 191)
    - Hens near a Mountain Village (Hühner bei Bergdorf), 618, 1919-1920 (Box 3, Folder 192)
    - Woman Resting with Folded Raised Arms (Ruhende Frau mit über dem Kopf verschränkten Armen), 618v, 1912 (Box 3, Folder 193)
    - The Old Farmer (Alter Bauer), 619, 1919/1920 (Box 3, Folder 194)
    - Girl in South Wind (Mädchen im Föhn), 620, 1919-1920 (Box 3, Folder 195)
    - Self Portrait with a Cat (Selbstporträt mit Katze), 621, 1920 (Box 3, Folder 196)
    - Old Peasant; "The Korean" (Alter Bauer; "Koreaner"), 622, 1920 (Box 3, Folder 197)
    - Girl in the Meadow; Daughter Lange (Mädchn in der Weise; Tocher Lange), 623, 1920 (Box 3, Folder 198)
    - The Two Mardersteig Brothers (Zwei Brüder Mardersteig), 624, 1920 (Box 3, Folder 199)
    - Attic Corner; Studio Corner (Estrichecke; Atelierecke), 625, 1920 (Box 3, Folder 200)
    - The Painter; Self-Portrait by the Window (Der Maler; Selbstbildnis am Fenster), 626, 1920/1921 (Box 3, Folder 201)
    - Artist; Marcella (Artistin; Marcella), 626v, 1910 (Box 3, Folder 202)
    - Interior with Painter (Interieur mit Maler), 627, 1920 (Box 3, Folder 203)
    - Girl with Wooden Sculpture before the Window (Mädchenkopf mit Holzfigur am Fenster), 628, 1919-1920 (Box 3, Folder 204)
    - Female Portrait; Young Peasant Girl (Mädchenkopf; Portrait de jeune paysanne), 629, 1920/1922 (Box 3, Folder 205)
    - Mandoline Player (Mandolinistin), 630, 1920 (Box 3, Folder 206)
    - Our House; House in Meadow (Unser Haus; Haus in Wiesen), 631, 1920/1922 (Box 3, Folder 207)
    - Children on the Alp (Kinder auf der Alp), 632, 1920/1924 (Box 3, Folder 208)
    - Woman with Children; Strolling Family (Frau mit Knaben; Spaziergang), 633, 1920 (Box 3, Folder 209)
    - Meadows in Bloom (Blühende Wiesen), 634, 1920 (Box 3, Folder 210)
    - White Cow (Weiße Kuh), 635, 1920 (Box 3, Folder 211)
    - Herd of Goats Returning Home (Heimkehrende Ziegenherde), 636, 1920 (Box 3, Folder 212)
    - Cows Descending (Absteigende Kühe), 637, 1920 (Box 3, Folder 213)
    - Cows Descending (Absteigender Kühe), 638, 1920/1921 (Box 3, Folder 214)
    - Cows Returning Home (Heimkehr der Kühe), 639, 1919-1920 (Box 3, Folder 215)
    - Cows in the Evening (Kühe bei Sonnenuntergang), 640, 1919-1920 (Box 3, Folder 216)
    - Peasants in the Evening (Bauern am Abend), 641, 1920 (Box 3, Folder 217)
    - The Manure Cart (Der Mistwagon), 642, 1920 (Box 3, Folder 218)
    - Frauenkirch, 643, 1920 (Box 3, Folder 219)
    - Peasants at Midday (bauernmittag), 644, 1920 (Box 3, Folder 220)
    - Community Campfire (Bundesfeuer), 645, 1920/1921 (Box 3, Folder 221)
    - Peasant Group (Bauerngruppe), 646, 1920-1921 (Box 3, Folder 222)
    - Mountain Hay-Gatherers; Haying on the Alps (Bergheuer; Heuer auf der Alp), 647, 1920/1921 (Box 3, Folder 223)
    - Sleeping Peasants; Reclining Cowherds (Ausruhende Bauern; Liegende Hirten), 648, 1920/1921 (Box 3, Folder 224)
    - Kummeralp Mountain and Two Sheds (Kummeralpberg und zwei Ställe), 649, 1920 (Box 3, Folder 225)
    - Mountain Hunter (Bergjäger), 650, 1920/1922 (Box 3, Folder 226)
    - The Blue Tree; Mountain Forest (Der blaue Baum; Bergwald), 651, 1920/1922 (Box 3, Folder 227)
    - Tree at the Curve (Baum in der Kurve), 652, 1920 (Box 3, Folder 228)
    - Timberline Firs; Firs in the Mountains (Grenztannen; Tannen im Gebirge), 653, 1920 (Box 3, Folder 229)
    - Noontime, Mountain Forest (Bergwald Mittag), 654, 1920/1921 (Box 3, Folder 230)
    - The Gorge (Das Tobel), 655, 1920 (Box 3, Folder 231)
    - Frauenkirch in Autumn (Frauenkirch im Herbst), 656, 1920 (Box 3, Folder 232)
    - Peasant Dance (Bauerntanz), 657, 1919-1920 (Box 3, Folder 233)
    - Peasants in the Evening; Tango-Tea (Bauern am Abend; Tangotee), 658, 1919-1920 (Box 3, Folder 234)
    - Tango-Tea (Tangotee), 659, 1919-1921 (Box 3, Folder 235)
    - Peasant Dance (Bauerntanz), 660, 1920/1938 (Box 3, Folder 236)
    - Still Life with China (Stilleben mit chinesischem Porzellan), 661, 1920/1932 (Box 3, Folder 237)
    - Mountain Brook with Footbridge in the Woods (Bergbach mit Steg im Wald), 662, 1921 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Alp Path; Mountain Path (Alpweg; Bergweg), 663, 1921 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Mountain Shepherd in Autumn (Berghirte im Herbst), 664, 1921 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Farmer in the Stable; Farmer Schmid (Bauer im Stall; Bauer Schmid), 665, 1921 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Resting Peasant Family (Rastende Bauernfamilie), 666, 1921-1923 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Two Nudes on the Mountain (Zwei nackte Mädchen am Berg), 667, 1921 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Two Nudes in the Forest (Zwei nackte Frauen im Wald), 668, 1921 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Landscape with Two Nudes (Zwei weibliche Akte in Landschaft), 669, 1921 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Nude descending the Muntain (Vom Berge steigende nackte Frau), 670, 1921 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Nude Woman and Child in the Snow (Frau und Mädchen nackt im Schnee), 671, 1921-1923 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Nude Girl Among the Reeds, Fehmarn (Nacktes Mädchen im Schilf, Fehmarn), 671v, 1911 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Lady in the Forest; Portrait of Nina Hard (Dame im Wald; Porträt Nina Hard), 672, 1921 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - The Dancer Nina Hard (Tänzerin Nina Hard), 673, 1921 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Reclining Dancer; Nude on Carpet (Liegende Tänzerin; Nacktes Mädchen auf Teppich), 674, 1921 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Team of Horses with Three Peasants (Pferdegespann mit drei Bauern), 675, 1920-1921 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - The Mountains (Die Berge), 676, 1921 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - The Wanderer (Der Wanderer), 677, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Anthony and Cleopatra (Antonius und Cleopatra), 678, 1921-1923 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - The Murder of Amelia (Ermordung der Amelia), 679, 1921-1923 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Marriage (Die Verbinderung), 680, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Nudes Standing by the Stove (Stehende nackte Mädchen am Ofen), 680v, 1908 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - The Meadow-Saffron (Die Herbstzeitlos), 681, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Shepherd (Hirte), 682, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - The Sick One (Der Kranke), 683, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - The Overturned Tree (Der gestürzte Baum), 684, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Mountain Landscape (Gebirgslandschaft), 685, 1921-1923 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Staffelalp Gorge II (Tobel der Staffelalp II), 685v, 1919 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Alp Path after the Storm (Alpweg nach dem Gewitter), 686, 1922/1923 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Green Self-Portrain in Landscape (Grünes Selbstbildnis vor Landschaft), 687, 1922/1924 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Peasant Woman wiht Child; the Storyteller (Bäuerin mit Kind; Märchenzählerin), 688, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Interior (Interieur), 689, 1921-1923 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Nude with Figure of a Mann (Weiblicher Akt mit männlicher Figur), 690, 1921-1923 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Harem (Harem), 691, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Woman and Girl; Mother and Daughter (Frau und Mädchen; Mutter und Mädchen), 692, 1922-1923 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - The Visit; Couple and Guest (Der Besuch; Paar und Ankömmling), 693, 1922-1923 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Peasants with Shovels by Mountain Brook (Bauern mit Schaufeln am Bergbach), 694, 1921-1923 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Five Children in Front of the House (Fünf Kinder vor dem Haus), 695, 1921-1923 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Man Blowing his Nose (Sich die Nase schneuzender Mann), 696, 1921-1923 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Water Carrier at the Mountain Brook (Wasserträger am Bergbach), 697, 1921-1923 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Flower Still Life (Blumenstilleben), 697v, 1913 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Portrait of Jakob Bosshart (Porträt Bosshart), 698, 1921-1923 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Two Painters; Kündig and Meyer-Amden (Zwei Maler; Kündig und Meyer-Amden), 699, 1921-1923 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Heads of Three Peasants (Drei Bauernköpfe), 700, 1921-1923 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Mountain Landscape with Cabins (Berglandschaft mit Hütten), 701, 1921-1923 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Three Peasants (Drei Bauern), 702, 1921-1923 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Before Milking-Time (Vor dem Melken), 703, 1922-1923 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Reclining Peasant with Pipe (Liegender Bauer mit Pfeife), 704, 1922-1923 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Three Peasants (Drei Bauern), 705, 1921-1923 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Peasant Family Meal (Bauernfamilie beim Essen), 706, 1922-1923 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Three Peasants (Drei Bauern), 707, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Italian Railroad Worker (Italienische Bahnarbeiter), 708, 1923 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - The Flute Player (Der Flötenspieler), 709, 1922-1923 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Sunday in the Alps, Small Version (Alsonntag, kleine Fassung), 710, 1922-1923 (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Sunday in the Alps (Alpsonntag), 711, 1922-1923 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Melting Snows; Muntain Landscape with Hut (Schneesmelze; Berglandschaft mit Alphütte), 712, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Country Road and Hut (Landstrasse und Hütte), 712v, 1909-1910 (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Sleigh Ride (Die Schlittenfahrt), 713, 1922/1926 (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Boy with Horn; Boy in Winter Landscape (Knabe mit Horn; Knabe im Winterlandschaft), 714, 1922-1923 (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Sertig Valley; Sertig Road in the Snow (Sertigtal; Sertigweg im Schnee), 715, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Winter in Davos (Winter in Davos), 718, 1921-1923 (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - The First Snow (Der erste Schnee), 717, 1921-1923 (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - Winter in Davos (Winter in Davos), 718, 192-1923 (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - Larch-Trees in Early Mountain Spring (Berg-Vorfrühling mit Lärchen), 719, 1921-1923 (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - Tall Pines in Front of Hills (Hohe Kiefern vor Hügellandschaft), 720, 1921-1923 (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - Trees in Blossom on Colorful Field (Blühende Bäume auf buntem Feld), 721, 1921-1923 (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - Mountain Valley with Enclosed Cow Pasture (Bergtal mit Kugehege), 722, 1921-1923 (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - Mountain Lake and Houses in Snow (Bergsee und Häuser im Schnee), 723, 1922-1923 (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - Peasant Cart with Horse (Bauernwagen mit Pferd), 724, 1922-1923 (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - Nude by the Window (Nackte Frau am Fenster), 725, 1922-1923 (Box 4, Folder 69)
    - Circus Contortionist (Schlangenmensch), 726, 1922-1923 (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - Zurich Mills (Züricher Mühlen), 727, 1922-1923 (Box 4, Folder 71)
    - Girl in the Meadow (Mädchen in der Weise), 728, 1923/1926 (Box 4, Folder 72)
    - Portrait of Leon Schames (Mänerbildnis Leon Schames), 729, 1922/1924 (Box 4, Folder 73)
    - Studio Interior (Atelierinterieur), 730, 1921-1923 (Box 4, Folder 74)
    - The Living Room; Interior with Painter (Das Wohnzimmer; Interieur mit Maler), 731, 1923 (Box 4, Folder 75)
    - Lovers (Liebespaar), 732, 1921-1923 (Box 4, Folder 76)
    - Two Peasant Women with Child (Zwei Bäuerinnen mit Kind), 733, 1923 (Box 4, Folder 77)
    - Sunday in the Alps; Scene at the Well (Alpsonntag; Szene am Brunnen), 734, 1923-1924/1925 (Box 4, Folder 78)
    - Mountain Peasants on Sunday; Sunday in the Alps (Sonntag der Bergbauerm; Allpsonntag), 735, 1923-1924/1925 (Box 4, Folder 79)
    - Bathers in the Brook (Badende im Bach), 736, 1923 (Box 4, Folder 80)
    - Nude Couple by the Waterfall (Nacktes Paar am Wasserfall), 737, 1923 (Box 4, Folder 81)
    - Bathers (Badende), 738, 1923 (Box 4, Folder 82)
    - Nudes Bathing in Mountain Brook (In Bergbach badende nackte Frauen), 739, 1923 (Box 4, Folder 83)
    - Two Nudes (Zwei Frauenakte), 739v, 1911 (Box 4, Folder 84)
    - Sertig Mountains (Sertigberge), 740, 1923/1924 (Box 4, Folder 85)
    - The Amselfluh (Die Amselfluh), 741, 1923 (Box 4, Folder 86)
    - Two Cowboys with Cows (Zwei Kuhhirten mit Kühen), 742, 1923 (Box 4, Folder 87)
    - Portrait of the Sculptor Scherer (Scherer porträt mit zwei Holzfiguren), 743, 1923 (Box 4, Folder 88)
    - Dr. and Mrs. Schiefler (Schieflerpaar), 744, 1923 (Box 4, Folder 89)
    - The Pledge; Scene from Goethe's "Götz von Berlichingen" (Das Versprechen; Hutten begrüßt Sickingen), 745, 1923/1924 (Box 4, Folder 90)
    - Artist on the Rings (Artisten am Ringen), 746, 1923/1928 (Box 4, Folder 91)
    - Gymnasts' Parade (Turnerumzug), 747, 1923 (Box 4, Folder 92)
    - Wrestlers (Ringer), 748, 1923 (Box 4, Folder 93)
    - Black Springtime (Schwarzer Frühling), 749, 1923 (Box 4, Folder 94)
    - Bathers at the Lake; Rape of the Sabines (Badende; Raub der Sabinerinnen), 750, 1923/1934 (Box 4, Folder 95)
    - Log Carriers (Holzträger), 751, 1923 (Box 4, Folder 96)
    - The Appearance of the Seven in the Eulenspiegel (Die Erscheinung der Sieben im Eulenspiegel), 752, 1923-1924 (Box 4, Folder 97)
    - Eulenspiegel and Lamm in the Bordello (Eulenspiegel und Lammi im Bordello), 753, 1923-1924 (Box 4, Folder 98)
    - Afternoon Coffee (Kaffeetisch), 754, 1923 (Box 4, Folder 99)
    - Nighttime Scene, Peasants by their Cabin (Nächtlinge Szene mit Bauern vor der Hütte), 755, 1922-1924 (Box 4, Folder 100)
    - Woman with Child (Mädchen mit Kind), 756, 1924/1926 (Box 4, Folder 101)
    - The Sertig Path in Summer (Sertigweg im Sommer), 757, 1924 (Box 4, Folder 102)
    - The Path to Sertig (Sertigweg), 758, 1924/1926 (Box 4, Folder 103)
    - Sertig Valley (Sertigtal), 759, 1924 (Box 4, Folder 104)
    - Roads through the Züge Mountains (Zügenbahnstraße), 760, 1924/1926 (Box 4, Folder 105)
    - Our House Wildboden (Unser Haus Wildboden), 761, 1924 (Box 4, Folder 106)
    - Night Moon; Accordian Player by Moonlight (Mondnacht; Handorgler in Mondnacht), 762, 1924 (Box 4, Folder 107)
    - The Friends; Albert Müller and H. Scherer (Die Freunde), 763, 1924/1925 (Box 4, Folder 108)
    - Train Station (Bahnhof), 764, 1924-1925 (Box 4, Folder 109)